SIEGFRED SAMSON

6, KIKUYU CLOSE, WUSE 2 ABUJA / (+234) 803 619 2916

siegfredsamson@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/siegfred/ | https://github.com/siegfred14

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am a people-friendly individual who is decision and result oriented, coachable and with good communication skills. As an avid learner, I am comfortably a team player who is largely attracted by the effects of technology on daily affairs, especially as it relates to business, health, community development and human advancement. In addition to my skills and experience in web development, software engineering, sales and marketing, computer engineering, finance and banking, I am also bilingual. I am open to learning new methods to improve myself, my organization and environment by working in your company.

HIGHLIGHTS OF QUALIFICATIONS

- 2 years in web development, with experience in both **frontend** and **backend** development.
- 7 years in Marketing and Public Relations with experience in Digital Marketing, Business Development, Public Speaking, and leading Teams across continents.
- 2 years in **computer engineering**, working as a Systems Support Engineer.
- Fluent in English and French, with certified qualifications CLB 8 in International English Language Testing System (IELTS) and niveau B2 in Diplôme d'Etudes en Langue Française (DELF).
- Completed degree in Computer Science.
- Versatile in interpersonal relationships and willing to learn.

EXPERTISE

- Application Information Gathering
- Mark Up and Stylesheet Development
- Coding and debugging
- Hosting and Deployment

- Banking
- · Team Building and Leadership
- Sales and Marketing
- Public Speaking

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Frontend Web Developer

Code Clan Dev. - Nigeria

August 2014 - Present

- Receive requirements and forward to project manager
- Developing mark ups and stylesheets to translate requirements received
- Coding of functionalities using relevant language(s)
- Modifying existing software to rectify errors, upgrade interfaces and designs and refine functionality

Advertising, Marketing and Public Relations Officer

Alliance in Motion Global Nigeria Ltd - Abuja, Nigeria

Oct 2014 - Present

- Business strategy creation.
- Organization of plans and daily evaluation of organizational undertakings with regards to sales.
- Team Building and Leadership Training.
- Creation and delivery of public seminars to staff, prospective clients, stakeholders and shareholders.

Systems Support Engineer

OSLA Systems LTD - Abuja,

Sept 2012 – Sept 2014

- **Nigeria**
- Analyzing user requirements and design and develop system architecture and specifications.
- Performing research, design, development and integration of computer hardware such as bios, memory, storage and microprocessors
- Evaluating, documenting and optimizing capacity and performance of information and communication system networks.
- Undertaking research, design and development of network architecture of information and communication systems.

Banking Relationship Officer

Hedgeworth Microfinance Bank Aug 2009 - Aug 2012

Ltd - Abuja, Nigeria

- Development of banking products.
- Development of sale strategies and promotion techniques to drive up client base and bank deposit volume.
- Creating credit facilities
- Managing credit facilities from disbursement to liquidation.

• Managing credit racilities from dispursement to liquidation.	
EDUCATION	
La langue Francaise Niveau A1 à B2 Institut Francais Nigeria	Feb 2021 - Dec 2021
Bachelor of Science, Computer Science University of Abuja, Nigeria	Oct 2004 - Jan 2009
CERTIFICATES	
International Team Building and Leadership Convention Alliance in Motion Global Inc Manila Philippines	May 2019
Speakers Bureau (Stage and Public Speaking) Training Alliance in Motion Global Ltd - Abuja, Nigeria	Nov 2014
Marketing and Sales Techniques for Microfinance Banks DIL Consulting - Abuja, Nigeria	Nov 2010
Interconnecting Cisco Networking Devices (CCNA 640 – 802) HiiT - Lagos, Nigeria	Apr 2009